Exercise 1-29, Spelling and Numbers. Just as there is stress in words or phrases,
there is intonation in spelling and numbers. Americans seem to spell things
out much more than other people. In any bureaucratic situation, you'll be asked to
spell names and give all kinds of numbers, your phone number, your birth date, and so
on. There's a distinct stress and rhythm pattern to both spelling and numbers,
usually in groups of three or four letters or numbers, with the stress falling on the
last member of the group. Acronyms, phrases that are represented by the first
letter of each word, and initials are usually stressed on the last letter. Just
listen to the words as I say them, then repeat the spelling after me.
FBI, USMC, COD, SOS, XYZ, BOX, COOK, WIL, SON, 213, 911604, 9662, 1-800-457-4255,
915, 2.30. Midnight. Afternoon.